https://www.pratt.edu/the-institute/administration-resources/information-technology/pratt-institute-privacy-policy/

Pratt Institute Privacy Policy
Home /  The Institute /  Administration and Resources /  Information Technology /  Pratt Institute Privacy Policy
MENU
PRIVACY POLICY
Pratt's Privacy Policy pertains to any information we may collect from you through our Institute's website at www.pratt.edu as well as our affiliated websites. We are continually improving our privacy efforts in accordance with the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) on data protection and privacy, and the majority of our websites can be used without revealing any Personally Identifiable Information. For sites that require OneKey authentication, such as my.pratt.edu or lms.pratt.edu, some Personally Identifiable Information may be required and/or visible (i.e., information that can be used to identify you). Personally Identifiable Information can include information such as your name, email address, and image. You are responsible for ensuring the accuracy of the Personally Identifiable Information you submit to Pratt.
SITE USE AGREEMENT
By using our websites, you consent and agree that we may collect, use and disclose such Personally Identifiable Information in accordance with this Privacy Policy and as permitted or required by law. If you do not agree with these terms, please do not provide any Personally Identifiable Information to us. If you refuse or withdraw your consent, or if you choose not to provide us with any required Personally Identifiable Information, we may not be able to provide you with the services and information that we offer. Consent can be withdrawn at any time by contacting the Pratt Technology Desk at services@pratt.edu.
WHAT DATA IS COLLECTED?
We may collect Personally Identifiable Information provided directly by you when you become a student or employee of Pratt Institute. We may use your Personally Identifiable Information to contact you in various ways, such as email messages about important matters. We may also receive Personally Identifiable Information when you send us an email message or otherwise contact us. If you participate in an online course via the LMS or other online website we maintain, we may collect from you certain content, such as assignments you submit to instructors. We also collect course data, such as student responses to quizzes, exams, and surveys. You should not include any Personally Identifiable Information or other information of a sensitive nature, whether relating to you or another person, on assignments, exams, or surveys, except for information required to participate or submit such assignments, exams, or surveys.
HOW THIS DATA IS USED?
Pratt Institute will never disclose any of your Personally Identifiable Information. However, we may share your Personally Identifiable Information with various government authorities in response to subpoenas, court orders, or other legal process; to establish or exercise our legal rights or to protect our property; to defend against legal claims; or as otherwise required by law. In such cases we reserve the right to raise or waive any legal objection or right available to us. We also may share your Personally Identifiable Information when we believe it is appropriate to investigate, prevent, or take action regarding illegal or suspected illegal activities; to protect and defend the rights, property, or safety of Pratt Institute, the Site, our users, students, employees, or others; and in connection with this and other agreements. Pratt provides you with the ability to pay for Online Courses and other services using your Pratt Card or a credit card through a third party payment processing service provider. Please note that our service provider – not Pratt Institute – collects and processes your credit card information.
FERPA
The confidentiality, privacy, and accuracy of a student's record is maintained to the maximum extent possible. Student records are utilized and released only for the legitimate purposes and pursuits of students, faculty, staff, and the larger community. Any person who wishes to view a student's record or a portion thereof must request permission in writing which notes the date, the name of the user, and the student concerned, reason for access, and materials duplicated, if any.
COOKIES
A cookie is a small file that can be placed on your device that allows us to recognize you. It is sent to your browser and stored on your computer’s hard drive or tablet or mobile device. When you visit our sites, we may collect information from you automatically through cookies or a similar technology. We use cookies in very narrow circumstances, such as keeping you signed in, or storing classes that you have added to your shopping cart for the School of Continuing and Professional Studies. We will ask your consent before placing a cookie, and you have the right to refuse the use of cookies.
ANALYTICS
We use Google Analytics and Google Tag Manager as our data processor for gathering important data about our website usage. We use IP Anonymization and other tools to ensure no Personally Identifiable Information is captured or transmitted. Please see Google’s site on their privacy guidelines at privacy.google.com.
INFORMATION RETENTION
We keep your Personally Identifiable Information for no longer than necessary for the purposes for which it is used. The length of time we retain Personally Identifiable Information for depends on the purposes for which we collect and use it and/or as required to comply with applicable laws and to establish, exercise or defend our legal rights.
CONFIDENTIALITY
We consider the confidentiality and security of your information to be of the utmost importance. We will use industry standard physical, technical and administrative security measures to keep your Personally Identifiable Information confidential and secure and will not share it with third parties, except as otherwise provided in this Privacy Policy, or unless such disclosure is necessary in special cases, such as a physical threat to you or others, as permitted by applicable law. Because the Internet is not a completely secure environment, we cannot guarantee the security of Personally Identifiable Information, and there is some risk that an unauthorized third party may find a way to capture your information over the Internet. It is your responsibility to protect the security of your login information. Please note that e-mails communications are typically not encrypted and should not be considered secure. Pratt cannot guarantee the privacy or confidentiality of email, electronic documents, or other materials transmitted via the network. Any messages that are confidential as a matter of law should not be communicated via email.
MANAGING YOUR PERSONALLY IDENTIFIABLE INFORMATION
You have certain rights in relation to your Personally Identifiable Information. You can access your Personally Identifiable Information and confirm that it remains correct and up-to-date or choose whether or not you wish to receive material from us. If you would like further information in relation to your rights or would like to exercise any of them, you may also contact us via services@pratt.edu.
INTERNATIONAL TRANSFER
Pratt Institute Sites are primarily operated and managed on servers located and operated within the United States. In order to provide our services to you, we may send and store your Personally Identifiable Information outside of the country where you reside or are located, including to the United States. Accordingly, if you reside or are located outside of the United States, your Personally Identifiable Information may be transferred outside of the country where you reside or are located, including to countries that may not or do not provide the same level of protection for your Personally Identifiable Information. We are committed to protecting the privacy and confidentiality of Personally Identifiable Information when it is transferred. If you reside or are located within the EEA and such transfers occur, we take appropriate steps to provide the same level of protection for the processing carried out in any such countries as you would have within the EEA to the extent feasible under applicable law.
PRATT CARD
Any personal information collected for the PrattCard, including personal images, will only be used for Institute purposes and within the established guidelines. Any data collected on the use of the Institute facilities and services by the cardholder will be treated in the same manner. Information regarding the cardholder will not be provided to third parties unless required by law or with written permission of the cardholder. Information regarding cardholder(s) is considered strictly confidential and is securely maintained. Cardholder information will only be shared in the following manner unless the cardholder has signed a privacy waiver; completion of a transaction, verification of account, compliance with judicial order or a lawfully issued subpoena.
WEB ACCESSIBILITY
Pratt Institute is committed to its policy that persons with disabilities have a full and equal opportunity to benefit from the goods, services, privileges, advantages, and accommodations offered by Pratt Institute. In keeping with that policy, Pratt Institute has retained an accessibility consultant to implement and maintain compliance with the relevant portions of the World Wide Web Consortium's Web Content Accessibility Guidelines 2.0 Level AA (WCAG 2.0 AA) as well as state and federal accessibility requirements. As part of this commitment, we are continually improving our website at www.pratt.edu to make it more accessible. If you encounter any difficulty using our website, have suggestions about improving the usability or accessibility of the website, or would like to know more about Pratt Institute's commitment to accessibility, please contact the service desk by emailing services@pratt.edu.
POLICY CHANGES
Please note that we review our privacy practices periodically, and that these practices are subject to change. Any change, update, or modification will be effective immediately upon posting on our Site. If you have any privacy-related questions, suggestions, unresolved problems, or complaints you may contact us via services@pratt.edu.
Office of the President
Office of the Provost
Finance and Administration
Communications and Marketing
Information Technology
Educational Technology
HEOA Anti-Piracy
Information Technology Staff
Telepresence Cloud Kit
Interested in applying to Pratt? Learn more.
Pratt Online Consent Agreement
By clicking agree or continuing to surf this site's pages you understand that Pratt Institute may collect information that has been provided by you. To learn more about Pratt’s privacy policy, visit www.pratt.edu/privacy.
Agree
